<resources>
    <string name="app_name">JamesApp</string>
    <string name="mercury_name">Memory</string>
    <string name="earth_name">About</string>
    <string name="mars_name">Wallpaper</string>
    <string name="jupiter_name">Space</string>
    <string name="saturn_name">Space</string>
    <string name="uranus_name">Space</string>
    <string name="neptune_name">Space</string>
    <string name="venus_name">Quiz</string>
    <string name="solar_orbit">
        A Solar Orbit

The James Webb Space Telescope will not be in orbit around the Earth, like the Hubble Space Telescope is - it will actually orbit the Sun, 1.5 million kilometers (1 million miles) away from the Earth at what is called the second Lagrange point or L2. What is special about this orbit is that it lets the telescope stay in line with the Earth as it moves around the Sun. This allows the satellite\'s large sunshield to protect the telescope from the light and heat of the Sun and Earth (and Moon).
    </string>
    <string name="L2">
        What is L2?

Joseph-Louis Lagrange was an 18th century mathematician who found the solution to what is called the “three-body problem.” That is, is there any stable configuration, in which three bodies could orbit each other, yet stay in the same position relative to each other? As it turns out, there are five solutions to this problem - and they are called the five Lagrange points, after their discoverer. At Lagrange points, the gravitational pull of two large masses precisely equals the centripetal force required for a small object to move with them. The L1, L2, and L3 points are all in line with each other - and L4 and L5 are at the points of equilateral triangles.
+
Diagram showing the Sun, the Earth, Webb, and the Lagrange points
Lagrange Points.

The first Sun-Earth Lagrange point, L1, is 1.5 million km from the Earth towards the Sun, and there have been many solar observatories located here, including DSCOVR, WIND, SOHO, and ACE.

There have been other satellites out at Sun-Earth L2, where Webb will be, including WMAP, Herschel, and Planck.
    </string>

    <string-array name="gameModeArray">
        <item>2x2</item>
        <item>4x4</item>
        <item>6x6</item>
        <item>8x8</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="resultText">Затраченное время\n</string>

    <string name="memory">
        Among its most important goals, JWST will see the light from the universe’s first stars and galaxies.
    </string>

    <string name="memory14">
        MIRI is inspected in the giant clean room at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center in Greenbelt, Maryland, in 2012. Credit: NASA/Chris Gunn.
    </string>
    <string name="memory13">
        Hubble Space Telescope images in the optical (top) and near-infrared (bottom) of the Eagle Nebula’s Pillars of Creation. These images show how infrared light can peer through obscuring dust and gas and reveal star and planet formation within these giant galactic stellar nurseries. Credit: NASA, ESA/Hubble and the Hubble Heritage Team.
    </string>
    <string name="memory12">
        A prototype of a mask used in the Canadian NIRISS instrument in AMI mode, showing the layout of the seven hexagonal holes in the mask with respect to the Webb primary mirror segments and secondary mirror supports. (Credit: Anand Sivaramakrishnan/Space Telescope Science Institute)
    </string>
    <string name="memory11">
        Part of the Webb team in front of a full-scale model at NASA’s Goddard Space Flight Center in Greenbelt, Maryland, in 2005. Credit: NASA
    </string>
    <string name="memory10">
        Jupiter and some of its moons are seen through NIRCam’s 3.23 micron filter. Credits: NASA, ESA, CSA, and B. Holler and J. Stansberry (STScI)
    </string>

    <string name="memory9">
        The James Webb Space Telescope will not be in orbit around the Earth, like the Hubble Space Telescope is - it will actually orbit the Sun, 1.5 million kilometers (1 million miles) away from the Earth at what is called the second Lagrange point or L2.
    </string>

    <string name="memory8">
        Orion is NASA\'s new exploration spacecraft, designed to carry astronauts to destinations in deep space, including an asteroid and Mars.
    </string>
    <string name="memory7">
        NASA - National Aeronautics and Space Administration.
    </string>
    <string name="memory6">
        Gold layers plating the scope’s mirrors are only 1,000 atoms thick. Indeed, only a golf-ball-sized amount of gold was used to coat the entire 21-foot-wide mirror.
    </string>
    <string name="memory5">
        On December 25, 2021, the telescope was successfully launched from the Kourou spaceport using the Ariane-5 rocket.
    </string>
    <string name="memory4">
        The largest space telescope with the largest mirror
    </string>
    <string name="memory3">
        Perseverance rover will look for signs of past microbial life, cache rock and soil samples, and prepare for future human exploration.
    </string>
    <string name="memory2">
         1.5 million kilometers (1 million miles) away from the Earth at what is called the second Lagrange point or L2.
    </string>
    <string name="memory1">
        Unique image of jupiter from James Webb
    </string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="fact_webbs_telescope">One Side of the Telescope Is Hotter Than Death Valley, the Other Side Is Colder Than Antarctica</string>
    <string name="memory_title">James\nApp</string>
</resources>